어때? '조이의 보금자리'
So what do you think?
Casa de Joey.
-I decorated it myself.
-Get out!
내가 직접 꾸몄어
- 설마
- 정말?
Wow, Joey, this is....
조이, 이건...
-Art.
-Art it is.
- 예술이지
- 예술 그 자체네
이것 봐, 커피 탁자인가? 표범?
꼭 결정할 필요는 없어
Check this out!
Is it a coffee table?
Is it a panther?
There's no need to decide.
쿠션 멋진데
Hey, nice pillow.
이거 진짜 타조 털 맞아?
So tell me,
is this genuine Muppet skin?
멋있다
굉장한 물 받침대네
Hey, excellent water, table thing.
Thanks. I love this.
But you know what?
고마워, 나도 맘에 드는데
이것만 보면 오줌이 마렵더라
It makes me want to pee.
Yeah, me too.
I think that's the challenge.
나도 그런데
그 점이 흥미로운 거야
그런데 챈들러는 안 왔네
How come Chandler didn't come?
할 일이 있대, 할 일이...
It's because he had
a thing with the...
...with the thing.
Right. I got it.
그래, 알겠어
So why don't you show us
the rest of your casa?
'조이의 보금자리'
다른 곳도 구경시켜 줘야지
제일 멋진 곳! 이리 와
The best part! Come on.
어때?
어머...
Nice toilet.
변기 죽인다
No, no, no. Behind it.
아니, 뒤를 봐
-You have a phone in here?
-That's right.
- 여기다 전화를 뒀어?
- 그거야
I have a phone.
전화도 있다
변소에 말야
In here.
조이, 나랑 약속 하나 해
Joey, promise me something.
Never call me from that phone.
저걸로 나한테 걸지 마
The One Where Eddie Moves ln
Okay, here we go.
여기 나왔어
Sorry, they were all out of apple pie.
Someone just got the last piece.
미안, 애플파이가 다 떨어졌어
마지막 걸 방금 누가 챙겼어
얘들아, 나 좀 봐
이 사실 절대 못 믿을 거야
Oh, my God!
You won't believe this!
누가 날 발굴했어!
I have just been discovered.
Wait a minute. I claimed you
in the name of France four years ago.
난 벌써 4년 전에 네 이름이
프랑스식이라고 부르짖었다
어쨌든 약속해
Anyway.
Don't freak out and say how
great this is until I'm done.
절대 흥분하지 않고
끝까지 들어주기로
레코드사 프로듀서를 만났는데
내 목소리가 참신하고 독특하대
I just met this producer
of this teeny record company...
...who said that I have
a very fresh, offbeat sound...
내 노래 '냄새나는 고양이'의
데모 테입을 만들겠대
...and she wants to do
a demo of "Smelly Cat."
아직 안 끝났어
Okay, I told you not to do that yet.
뮤직비디오도 만들 거래
And she wants to do a video.
아직 안 끝났어
I'm not done yet, okay?
God!
세상에...
잘되면 앨범도 만들어 준대
If that goes well,
they may even want to make an album.
I'm done now.
이제 끝났어
- 대단하다!
- 믿어지지가 않아
If you care about me,
get the pie out of the man's hood.
로스, 날 정말 좋아한다면
저 남자 모자에서 파이를 꺼내
- 뭘 꺼내?
- 모자에 파이가 있어, 가!
-Get the what?
-There's a pie in the hood. Go!
What are you doing?
뭐 하쇼?
죄송해요, 제 파이가
댁의 모자에 있네요
I'm sorry.
My pie was in your hood.
I have to get the coffee
out of that guy's pants...
저 남자 바지에선 커피를 빼고
7시엔 병원에 돌아가야지
...and I'll be back
in the hospital by 7.
Damn it, Ross!
Get your butt out of the bathroom!
뭐 해, 오빠
빨리 나오란 말야
기다려, 머리 말리고 있어
Calm down. I'm blow-drying.
머리카락도 없으면서 뭘 말려?
Blow-drying what?
You have no hair.
What's going on?
왜 그래?
네 남자친구가 1시간 넘게
저러고 있잖아
Your boyfriend has been
in there for an hour!
또 오빠랑 살게 되다니!
It's like I'm living with him again.
자러 갈 때도 있더니 일어나서
샤워하러 와 보니 또 있어
He's here when I go to sleep and
wake up and when I want to shower.
다시 16살로 돌아간 것 같아
I feel like I'm 16 again.
넌 16살이 아냐
우리 둘 다 어른이라구
Well, you're not 16.
You're both adults now.
얼른 나와, 굼뱅아!
Get out, you doofus!
Or, you know,
he's rubber and you're glue.
네 오빤 끈끈이고
넌 찐득이 같아
이제 너 써라
All yours.
I hope you cleaned your hair
out of the drain.
배수구에 떨어진 머리카락
다 치웠어?
- 하지 마
Shut up!
그만 해!
Cut it out!
다신 그러지 마
I've never wanted you more.
So what do you say, boys?
Should I call him?
어떻게 할까?
조이한테 전화 걸어?
얘가 뭐랬는 줄 아니?
You know what they say:
슬리퍼한테 물어 보래
Ask your slippers a question...
너도 미쳐 가는구나
...you're going crazy.
- 여보세요?
- 이봐
야!
오늘 못 가서 미안해
I'm sorry I didn't make it
over there today.
괜찮아, 할 일이 있었다며?
That's okay.
You had a thing.
네 집 아주 근사하다며?
I hear the place looks great.
아냐, 축구 게임기도 없는데 뭐
Forget about it.
I'm having a ball!
거긴 어때?
How's the apartment?
아주 좋아, 평소처럼...
축제 분위기지 뭐
It's terrific.
I mean, it's a regular space-...
...-fest!
잘됐다
Well, great.
그냥...
Yeah, I just...
...wanted to call and say hey.
인사나 하려고 전화했어
Well, okay.
난 잘 있어
그거 타이머 소리야?
Was that the oven timer?
맞아, 역시 넌 내 친구야
That's right, my friend.
할 시간 됐다
It's time for...
'해양구조대'!
...Baywatch!
스테파니가 피부암이라니
믿어지니?
Can you believe they gave
Stephanie skin cancer?
I can't believe
they made her lieutenant!
저 여자랑 경위가 어울리냐?
그럼 야스민 블릭이
너랑 어울린다는 거냐?
You're saying that because
you love Yasmine Bleeth.
어떤 놈이 야스민 블릭을
안 좋아할 수 있겠어?
How could anyone
not love Yasmine Bleeth?
저것 봐! 달린다!
Hey, they're running.
이 부분이 클라이맥스야
See, this is the
brilliance of the show.
계속 달리기만 했으면 좋겠어!
I say always keep them running.
All the time running!
계속 달리는 거야, 달려!
Run!
달려라!
달려, 야스민
바람처럼 달려라!
Run, Yasmine! Run like the wind!
But you wanted to live by yourself.
넌 혼자 살고 싶어했잖아
그랬지, 그럼 행복할 줄 알았어
I did. I thought it'd be great.
혼자 생각할 시간을 갖고 싶었지
I figured I'd have time alone
with my thoughts.
그런데 생각할 게 별로 없더라
But it turns out I don't have
as many thoughts as you think.
그럼 챈들러한테 다시
합치자고 말해 봐
Why don't you talk to Chandler
about moving back?
날 받아줄까?
You really think he'd take me?
어젯밤엔 기분 좋게 통화했지만
워낙 심하게 다투고 나와서
We had a good talk last night...
...but when I moved out,
I hurt him bad.
분명히 네가 오길 바랄 거야
He would definitely want you back.
조이가 다시 올 가능성은
전혀 없어
I'm telling you,
there's no way he's moving back.
어젯밤에 난생 처음
기분 좋게 통화했어
But we had one of the greatest talks
we ever had last night.
맨 처음 같이 살 때처럼
분위기가 좋았다고
I mean, it was
It was like when we first
started living together.
이런 말 듣긴 싫겠지만
I know you don't want
to hear this right now...
조이는 새 집에서 잘 살고 있어
지금 행복해 한다고
... but we've seen him
in his new place. And he's happy.
집까지 직접 꾸몄어
He's decorated.
조이는 잘해 나가니까
너도 그래야 해
Chandler, he has moved on, okay?
You have to, too.
- 하지만...
- 안 돼, 사실을 받아들여
You'll have to accept the fact
that you're just friends now.
너흰 이제 그냥 친구지
룸메이트가 아냐!
You're not...
... roommates anymore.
피비, 준비됐어요?
Okay, Phoebe.
You ready to try one?
네
Smelly cat, smelly cat
냄새나는 고양아...
뭘 먹었니?
What are they feeding you?
Smelly, smelly, smelly
Really bad smelling smelly cat
냄새, 냄새가 지독한 고양이
Whoa! Oh, my God!
어머! 놀래라
누구 목소리죠?
I mean, like, who was that?
백코러스예요
뒤에 있어요
They're your backup singers.
Behind you, hon.
날 구경하는 줄 알았는데
I thought they were just watching me.
꼭 수족관 같네요
Like at an aquarium, you know?
All right.
좋아요, 피비
From the top.
- 처음부터 해봐요
- 네
냄새나는 고양아
뭘 먹었니?
Smelly cat, smelly cat
What are they feeding you?
냄새, 냄새가 지독한 고양이
네 잘못이 아니란다
미안해요
Okay, sorry.
여기 나오는 고양이의 냄새가
얼마나 지독한지 다들 아나요?
I'm just not getting...
...that everyone gets...
... how smelly
this cat actually is.
노래에 대해 토론을 해야 돼요
고양이를 정말 사랑해야 해요!
Maybe if we could talk about this...
... because I need to feel
that you really care about the cat.
피비, 얘기도 좋지만 이 곳의
사용료가 분당 100달러예요
We can talk.
It's just that this costs
$100 a minute to be in here.
고양이는 냄새가 지독해도
사랑스러워요, 시작하죠
So the cat stinks,
but you love it. Let's go.
밸로시랩터라니 말도 안 돼
No, there is no way
he was a velociraptor.
Look at the cranial ridge, okay?
아냐, 두개골을 봐
If Dino was a velociraptor,
he'd have eaten the Flintstones.
디노가 밸로시랩터라면
부싯돌을 먹었을 거 아냐
그래
- 너 낮잠 자고 있었니?
- 그랬지
Were you taking a nap?
I was.
기다려, 토니
다른 전화 좀 받을게
Tony, can you hold on?
That's the other line.
여보세요? 모니카 여기 있어요
전화하라고 할까요?
Yeah, she's here,
but can she call you back?
네, 잘 있어요
Okay, thanks.
조안나 전화야, 여보세요?
Call Joanna.
- 전화번호 남겼어?
- 내가 받아 적는 것 봤어?
Did she leave a number?
Did you see me write one down?
전화번호 몰라, 멍청하긴
I don't have her number, butt-munch.
다시 전화하겠지
애처럼 그러지 좀 마
She'll call back.
Don't be such a baby.
난 애가 아냐
오빠가 애 같지
You're the baby.
- 내 뒤에서 사라져 줄래?
- 내 앞에서 없어져 줄래?
-Get off my back.
-Get out of my face.
잠깐 기다려, 토니
Wait, hold on, Tony. Hold on.
여보세요? 네
모니카 있어요, 잠깐만요
Yeah, she's right here.
Hold on.
토니, 내가 다시 걸게
여동생 애인한테 전화 왔거든
Tony, can I call you back?
That's my sister's boyfriend.
이리 줘
Give me that.
저예요, 혹시 당신 집에
내 피임약 두고 왔어요?
Sweetie, before I forget, did l
leave my diaphragm at your place?
Hi, Mom.
엄마!
궁전에서 사는 소감이 어때?
So how's the palace?
그런 말 하니까 우습다
왜냐하면...
It's funny you should mention that
because I was thinking....
What's with the boxes?
저 상자들은 뭐야?
저기... 새로운 소식이 있어
Actually, I have some news.
챈들러, 조이라는 친구한테
가져가랠까, 아님 그냥 버릴까?
Is that Joey guy gonna pick up
his moose hat or should I toss it?
직접 물어 봐
조이, 새 룸메이트 에디야
Why don't you ask him yourself?
This is my new roommate, Eddie.
- 반가워
- 나도 그래
Nice to meet you.
-Likewise.
-How you doing?
그건 내가 가질게
I'll take that.
이것 때문에 왔어
It's what I came for.
새거거든
This is new.
Where'd you two meet?
둘은 어떻게 만났어?
슈퍼의 외국음식 코너에서
At the supermarket
in the ethnic food section.
내가 코리초 고르는 걸
도와 줬지
I helped him pick out a chorizo.
얘기 중에 이 친구가 방이
필요하다잖아, 난 방이 남고...
We got to talking. He needed
a place, and I had a spare room.
이제 남는 방이 된 거야?
Now it's a spare room?
사용하지 않으니까
남는 방이 된 거지
Well, yeah.
In that it's not being used...
...and I have it to spare.
맞아, 그럼 볼일도 봤으니...
Well, I got what I came for.
다음에 보자
I'll see you.
조이!
Hey, Joe.
언제부터 뿔 달고 다녔어?
When'd you start using
moose in your hair?
이 친구 유머감각 끝내주지?
Is this guy great, or what?
그래, 그렇지
Yeah, he is.
룸메이트를 새로 구했다니
도대체 누구래?
I can't believe he has
a new roommate. Who is he?
Eddie. He just met him.
에디 뭐라고 하던데
확실히 모르겠어
It'll never last.
He's just a rebound roommate.
절대 오래 못 갈걸
반발심에 들였을 테니까
- 얘들아!
- 어서 와
이것 봐, '냄새나는 고양이'
비디오야
Check it out! Check it out!
It's "Smelly Cat," the video!
Now, I haven't seen it yet,
so if you don't like it...
나도 아직 못 봤어
너희들 맘에 안 들어도...
...so what?
None of you ever made a video.
상관없어, 너희들은
비디오 만든 적 없잖아?
'냄새나는 고양이' 피비 뷔페
감독:A체이스, BKC레코드
Get out of here, cat! You stink!
썩 나가라
이 냄새나는 것아!
- 끝내주는데!
- 너무 예쁘다!
Smoking!
나 좀 봐
Look at me!
냄새나는 고양아
뭘 먹었니?
Smelly cat, smelly cat
What are they feeding you?
냄새나는 고양아
네 잘못이 아니란다
Smelly cat, smelly cat
It's not your fault
Smelly, smelly, smelly
Really bad smelling smelly cat
냄새, 냄새 지독한 고양이
네 잘못이 아니란다
It's not your fault
냄새나는 고양이
Smelly cat, smelly cat
-Oh, my God!
-I know.
- 세상에!
- 글쎄 말야
내 목소리 너무 좋다
I sound amazing!
수의사한테 데려가지 않을걸
주인이 널 싫어하거든
They won't take you to the vet
You're obviously not their favorite pet
Smelly cat, smelly cat
냄새나는 고양아
네 잘못이 아니란다
It's not your fault
I've never heard myself sing before.
내 노래를 한 번도
들어 본 적이 없었어
I mean, except in my own head.
머리로 생각만 했지
정말 멋지다
너희들이 듣는 걸 나도 듣다니
This is so cool!
Now I can hear what you hear!
Pretty different, huh?
꽤 다르게 들리지?
그렇긴 한데
믿을 수 없을 정도로 잘하네
I am sorry,
but I'm incredibly talented!
냄새나는 고양이
네 잘못이 아니란다
Smelly cat, smelly cat
It's not your fault
조이, 웬일이야?
What's going on, man?
Eddie.
에디
Morning.
- 어서 와
- 그래
I just came by to pick up my mail.
내 우편물 가지러 왔어
-Where's the mail?
-Over there on the table.
- 어디 있어?
- 저 탁자 위에 있어
이제 여기다 안 두는 거야?
You don't keep it
on this table anymore?
에디가 저기 두고 싶대서
Eddie likes it over there.
All right, here you go, my friend.
Eggs a la Eddie.
다됐다, 여기 있어
에디식 달걀 요리
맛있는데
That's great.
What?
왜?
I thought you liked your eggs...
넌 노른자를 깨지 않고 빵에
끼워 먹기 좋아했잖아, 내 식대로
...with the bread with the hole
in the middle, a la me!
그래, 하지만 에디가 만들어 준
이것도 정말 맛있어
I do, but Eddie makes them this way.
They're pretty darn good.
친구들, 난 나가야겠어
Well, you guys...
... I'm out of here.
See you, pals.
- 이따 봐
See you.
-How are you two getting along?
-I couldn't be happier.
둘이 잘지내니?
더할 나위 없이 좋아
잘됐다, 축하해
Great.
I'm happy for you.
All right, that's it!
다 그만두자!
He just comes in here,
Mr. Johnny New Eggs...
저 '달걀 아무개' 씨가
여기를 차지했다 이거지?
...with his moving the mail
and his "See you, pals."
우편물도 맘대로 바꾸고
'이따 봐'라고?
게다가 주스도 없잖아
And now there's no juice!
There's no juice for the people
who need the juice. I need the juice!
주스를 마시고 싶은데 없어
난 주스가 마시고 싶다고!
There's another carton there.
저기 새 거 있어
This isn't about juice anymore,
all right, man?
지금 주스 얘기가 아니잖아
좋아, 그럼 뭐가 문제야?
All right.
So what's it about?
Eggs!
달걀!
어떤 게 더 좋아?
그 녀석 거야, 내 거야
Whose eggs do you like better,
his or mine?
-Well, I like both eggs equally.
-Oh, come on!
- 둘 다 똑같이 좋아
- 왜 이러셔!
Nobody likes two eggs equally.
I wanna know which one you like better.
완전히 다른 달걀을
똑같이 좋아하는 사람은 없어
둘 중 뭐가 더 좋아?
차이가 뭐냐고?
네 달걀은 더 이상 여기 없어
What's the difference?
Your eggs aren't here anymore.
넌 네 달걀을 갖고 나갔잖아
You took your eggs and you left!
Did you expect me
to never find new eggs?
나보고 죽을 때까지
새 달걀을 찾지 말라고?
I wanna watch Entertainment Tonight.
난 '연예가중계' 볼 거야
나도 고집 있어
'세렌게티의 침략자' 볼 거야
Tough. We're watching
Predators of the Serengeti.
둘 다 그만 좀 해
Would you guys stop!
이건 내 TV야
It's my TV!
그만 해!
-Quit it!
-Bite me!
- 약오르지?
- 맙소사!
모니카가 자꾸 채널을 바꾸잖아
Monica keeps changing the channel.
대단하셔
엄마한테도 이르지 그래?
That's great.
Why don't you tell Mommy on me?
이제 내가 엄마야
잘 들어!
Now I'm Mommy in this little play?
Look, I refuse to get sucked into...
난 이런 1차원적인 싸움에
끼여들기 싫어, 알겠어?
...this weird little Geller
dimension thing, okay?
So I'm gonna go take
a nice long hot bubble bath...
가서 거품목욕이나 할 거야
너희 둘 때문에 돌아 버리겠어!
...because you kids
are driving me crazy!
자, 어떻게 해결할 거야?
What do we do about this?
연예가중계를 녹화하면 되지
We could tape Entertainment Tonight.
TV가 아니라 우리 말야!
Not that!
This! Us!
오빠가 온 이후로 계속 이래
오빠가 날 미치게 한다구!
Oh, my God, Ross, it's....
You're just....
Since you've been here,
you're driving me....
모니카, 목소리가 또
찢어지기 시작하는구나
Mon, you've gone ultrasonic
again, all right?
난 오빠가 여기 있는 걸
참을 수가 없어
I just can't stand you being here...
...all the time!
Why? Why can't you
stand me being here?
왜 못 참는다는 거야?
얼마나 재미있니?
We're just having fun.
Fun? You think this is fun?
재미?
이게 재밌다고 생각해?
그래, 어릴 때처럼 이렇게
티격태격하는 게 좋잖아?
I thought we were fooling around,
like when we were kids.
I hated you when we were kids!
난 어렸을 때 오빠를 싫어했어
- 날 싫어했다구?
- 그래, 얼마나 미워했다구
You hated me when we were kids?
I hated you.
오빠니까 최소한의 애정은
있었지만 기본적으로 싫어했어
I loved you in a you're-my-brother-
so-l-have-to way...
... but basically, I hated your guts.
왜 날 싫어했어?
Why did you hate me?
Because you were mean to me...
왜냐하면 날 깔보고 괴롭히고
항상 오빠 식대로만 했잖아
...and you teased me
and you always got your way.
넌 그게 재미없었구나?
That wasn't fun for you?
전혀!
날 미워했다니
믿을 수가 없어
I can't believe you hated me.
지금이야 오빠를 좋아하지
But now I love you.
의무감 때문이 아니구
And not just because I have to.
- 정말?
- 그래
Really?
그러니 이제 나 좀
그만 괴롭혀
You're just gonna have
to stop pissing me off.
그럴게
I can do that.
그럼 나도 오빠를 살려 줄게
Then I won't have to kill you.
So you wanna watch
Entertainment Tonight?.
- 너 연예가중계 보고 싶다고?
- 고마워
Thanks.
- 있잖아
- 뭐
You know what?
세렌게티 어쩌고 하는 거
정말 보고 싶다면 봐
If you really wanna watch
that Serengeti thing, we can.
좋아
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
믿어지지 않겠지만 그 비디오
내가 부른 게 아니었어
Listen, you are not
going to believe this...
...but that is not me
singing on the video.
설마!
- 정말이야!
- 어떻게 알았어?
How did you find out?
레코드사가 서류에
사인을 하라는데
The record company sent this paper
for me to sign saying it's okay...
다른 사람이 불러도 좋다고
써 놨더라, 그게 단서였어
...for someone else to sing for me.
That was my first clue.
What will you do?
어떻게 할 건데?
I can't work with people
who would do this.
- 난 그런 사람들과는 일 못해
- 물론이지
Sure.
그 여자가 불쌍하잖아
I mean, this poor woman.
What woman?
그 여자라니?
노래부른 여자, 목소린 좋은데
비디오는 못 만들었잖아
The voice woman.
She has a great voice,
but she doesn't have a video.
좋아, 넌?
Okay, Pheebs, but what about you?
난 비디오라도 있지
중요한 건 그거야
I have a video. Pay attention.
This voice woman, she's so talented.
그 여자는 재능이 뛰어나
그런데 프로듀서 말이
외모가 딸려서 안 된대
But according to the producer people,
she doesn't have the right look.
꼭 동물수용소의 동물 같지?
못생겼다고 거들떠보지 않는...
She's like one of those
animals at the pound...
...who nobody wants
because they're not pretty.
Or you know, like some old dog
who's kind of like stinky and
늙고 지친 개나
냄새나고...
맞아! 그 여자가 바로
냄새나는 고양이야
Oh, my God! She's "smelly cat"!
내 노래에 수많은 의미가
담겨져 있구나
That song has so many levels.
에디, 나랑 축구게임 할래?
Hey, Eddie.
You wanna play some foosball?
난 스포츠엔 관심 없어
No, thanks, man.
I'm not really into sports.
Yeah, okay. All right.
그래...
- 'SOS 해양구조대' 할 시간이다!
- 뭐?
Doesn't matter.
Time for Baywatch!
그 드라마 좋아해?
You like that show?
넌 안 좋아해?
You don't?
잘생긴 남녀가 해변을
뛰어다니는 게 다잖아
It's just pretty people
running around on the beach.
그게 그 드라마의 묘미야
That's the brilliance of it.
잘생긴 사람들
The pretty people.
And the running.
달리기...
I'm gonna go read in my room
for a little while.
난 그냥 내 방에서
책이나 읽을게
좋아, 그래
Okay, man.
I think of all the friends I've known
But when I dial the telephone
No one's home
All by myself
Don't wanna live
Anymore
All by myself
냄새나는 고양아, 뭘 먹었니?
다같이!
Smelly cat, smelly cat
What are they feeding you?
Everybody!
냄새나는 고양아
네 잘못이 아니란다
Smelly cat, smelly cat
It's not your fault
모니카!
수의사한테 안 데려갈 거야
They won't take you to the vet
챈들러!
You're obviously not
their favorite pet
주인이 널 좋아하지 않거든
- 조이!
- 아늑한 잠자리는 없을 거야
You may not be a bed of roses
- 레이첼
- 그 냄새론 친구도 없을 거야
And you're no friend
To those with noses
로스, 가사는 여기까지야
다시 코러스!
Ross, those are the only lines we have.
Back to the chorus!